Go beyond the fairy tale.
Maleficent: Mistress of Evil is a family, fantasy,
adventure film directed by Joachim Rønning.
Maleficent and her goddaughter Aurora begin to question the complex family ties that bind them as they are pulled
in different directions by impending nuptials, unexpected allies, and dark new forces at play.
Maleficent, played by Angelina Jolie.
Princess Aurora, played by Elle Fanning.
Prince Phillip, played by Harris Dickinson.
Queen Ingrith, played by Michelle Pfeiffer.
Diaval, played by Sam Riley.
Conall, played by Chiwetel Ejiofor.
Maleficent: Mistress of Evil is a 2019 American fantasy film and a sequel to Maleficent (2014),
itself a live-action adaptation of Disney's 1959 animated film Sleeping Beauty.
Produced by Walt Disney Pictures and Roth/Kirschenbaum Films, it is
the second installment in the Maleficent film series.
The film was directed by Joachim Rønning and written by Linda
Woolverton, Micah Fitzerman-Blue, and Noah Harpster.
Angelina Jolie, Elle Fanning, Sam Riley, Imelda Staunton, Juno Temple, and Lesley Manville reprise their roles from the first
film, with Chiwetel Ejiofor, Harris Dickinson (replacing Brenton Thwaites), Ed Skrein, and Michelle Pfeiffer.
Set five years after the first film, the film sees Maleficent face the neighboring kingdom's manipulated perception of
herself as a villain, in addition to a subplot of the rise of an endangered, powerful fairy race of the Dark Fey.
After the release of the first film in May 2014,
Jolie stated a sequel was possible.
The project was officially announced the following June.
Jolie signed on in April 2016.
Rønning, who co-directed Pirates of the Caribbean: Dead Men Tell No Tales
(2017) for Disney, was hired to direct the film in October 2017.
The rest of the cast was added/confirmed in May 2018, with filming beginning that month
at Pinewood Studios in Buckinghamshire, England, lasting through August.
Maleficent: Mistress of Evil premiered in Los Angeles on September 30, 2019, and was released in
the United States theatrically on October 18 by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures.
It received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the performances of Jolie, Fanning, and
Pfeiffer, while criticizing the "muddled" plot and "overly artificial" visuals.
The film grossed $491 million worldwide, although it needed to make around $500 million in order to make
a profit theatrically when factoring in total budget, marketing and distribution costs.
It also received an Academy Award nomination for Best Makeup
and Hairstyling at the 92nd Academy Awards.
A third film is currently in development.
The film explores themes of magic, fairy tale,
fairy, live action remake, complicated.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.